我现在明白了
I see now
大冰封杀死了我所认识的每个人时
that as The Freeze killed everyone I ever knew,
我错把生存的机会当成了自由
I mistook my ticket to survival for freedom.
但正义没有上车
But justice never boarded,
威尔福德用守卫压迫我们
and Wilford doubled down with a Jackboot on our throats
只手操控一切
and a fat finger on the scales.
而今 我们中有些人想改变他的要求
Now some of us are ready to change his terms.
过程将危险而肮脏
It will be perilous, filthy work.
将有更多珍贵生命逝去
More precious souls may be lost.
克雷 我不想惹麻烦
Clay, I don't want any trouble.
我只是在工作 我不能卷进去
I'm just trying to work. I can't be involved.
你住在三等厢 这由不得你
You live in Third. You are involved.
但我们走到这一步 承受了那么多
But we didn't come this far, suffer this much
绝不会向当初
to give in to the same tyranny
毁了我们的暴行屈服
that destroyed us in the first place.
就算是在冰封的死亡星球上 人类也需要希望
Even on a frozen, dead planet, humanity needs hope.
因为这是我们在雪国列车上的革命
For these are our revolutions on Snowpiercer.
1001节车厢的革命
1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第五集
那是你妻子做的吗
Did your wife make that?
你们结婚多久了
How long have you been married?
你妻子叫什么
What's your wife's name?
你们在哪认识的
Where'd you guys meet?
在这里待了这么久 你还是不肯跟我说话吗
All this time in here, and you still won't talk to me?
你在这里说的话可以作为呈堂证供
What you say in here is admissible.
那又如何
So?
所以聪明的来客都闭上嘴
So our smart visitors stay quiet.
那是有罪的来客 我无可隐瞒
Your guilty visitors do. I have nothing to hide.
我父母是在瑞士圣莫里茨的缆椅上相识的
My parents met in St. Moritz, on a chairlift.
我知道你父母是谁
I know who your parents are.
不 你不知道 但你会知道的
No. No, you don't. But you will.
小莱 亲爱的 你没事吧
LJ, honey. Are you alright?
我们要带你回家
Oh, we are taking you home.
-梅兰妮 -亲爱的 我们好想你
- Melanie. - Sweetheart, we miss you so much.
你要跟我们回家
You're coming home with us.
小莱 你今天将接受谋杀审判
LJ, today you stand trial for murder.
你明白吗
Do you understand that?
是的
Yes.
你要代表自己发言
You'll be expected to speak on your own behalf,
由有票乘客组成的法庭将给出判决
and a tribunal of ticketed passengers will render a verdict.
明白了吗
Is that all clear?
威尔福德先生将会密切关注进展
Mr. Wilford will be following closely.
很好 那他就能看到这一切多么荒唐
Good. Then he can see how ridiculous this whole thing is.
去跟三名被害人所在的三等厢说啊
Tell it to Third, where the three victims lived.
她还是个孩子
She's just a child.
犯罪的人已经死了
The man who committed these crimes is dead.
而你把她关进了监狱
You just threw her in a cell.
你知道这在前车引发了怎样的反响吗
Do you have any idea how this is playing uptrain?
按照列车规矩 我们必须在审判前扣押她
We are bound by train rules to detain her ahead of trial.
仅此而已 莱拉
That's all, Lilah.
-没事的 -我不该进抽屉
- It's okay. - I don't belong in a drawer.
请送他们回房
Please escort them to their quarters.
我想感谢威尔福德先生给我机会证明这一点
And I just want to thank Mr. Wilford for the chance to prove it.
你觉得法庭判她有罪的可能性有多大
What are the chances you figure that the tribunal convicts her?
如果他们放了她 三等厢会动乱的
There's gonna be trouble in Third if they let her off.
已经有乱子了
There already is.
看来感染有所好转
It looks like the infection's improving.
你的扑克脸需要练习了 医生
Your poker face needs work, Doc.
我以前是兽医
I was a vet.
我的病人不会顶嘴
My patients didn't talk back.
有消息
Message!
阿斯特丽德又传来一条
Astrid sent another one.
"今天"
"Today"?
她想让我今天就去前车
She wants me uptrain today?
她一定是有莱顿的消息了
She must have some news on Layton.
准备好了吗 牛人
You ready, badass?
把芯片放在手链里
Put the chip in this bracelet.
一定要往上戴一些
Make sure you wear it nice and high.
-就像其他人一样在面板上刷一下 -好
- You're chipping the pad just like anyone else. - Yes.
小心点
Be careful.
这枚芯片可以让你进入二等厢
This chip will get you into Second Class.
成珍珠 作为此名升舱申请人的担保人
Jinju Seong, as Surety for this Upgrade Applicant,
你要为她在试用期中的行为
you accept liability for her conduct
承担责任 明白了吗
during her probationary period, understood?
明白 要是她乱来 我们都会遭殃
Yeah, if she messes up, we both suffer.
明白
Got it.
-这样就行了 贝丝 -谢谢 医生
- That should do it, Bess. - Thanks, Doc.
还有你的
And yours.
好了
Okay, then.
我谨代表威尔福德工业
On behalf of Wilford Industries,
在此授予你 贝丝·弗朗西斯·提尔
I hereby grant you, Bess Francis Till,
进入二等厢 以及其附带的所有权利
access to Second Class and all the entitlements therein.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们让你们俩好好庆祝一下
Well, I guess we should leave you two to celebrate.
看看我们
Look at us.
足足过了三个月才开始同居
Made it three whole months before shacking up.
我的个人最佳纪录
Personal best for me.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure about all this?
二等厢和附带的所有权利吗 不
Second Class and all the entitlements therein? No.
但从我们认识那天起 我就要定你了
But I was sure about you the day we met.
没人会给她定罪的
No one's going to convict her.
审判员都是付费乘客
The tribunal is paid passengers,
一等二等厢 我们都认识
First and Second. We know them.
就等你准备好了 宝贝
As long as you're prepared, sweetheart.
她会准备好的
She'll be prepared.
但在证人席上世事难料
But things happen on the stand --
-小莱 -注意听 宝贝
- LJ. - Pay attention, honey.
别玩了
Come on.
你们觉得抽屉里是什么样的
What do you think it's like in The Drawers?
你不用担心这些
Oh, you don't have to worry about that.
今晚一切就都结束了 你会回到我们身边
By tonight, this will all be over and you'll be back here with us.
爸爸
Dad.
我可以吗
Can I?
现在不行 小莱
Not now, LJ.
我想要
I want to.
没事的
It's fine.
看
Look.
好了 够了
Okay. That's enough.
吐出来
Spit it.
今天可不是胡闹的时候
It's not a day for your antics.
你嘴里只应该吐出来这些字
The only thing that should be in your mouth are these words --
"他逼我的"
"He forced me."
的确是他逼我的
He did force me.
你们知道的吧
You do know that, right?
我们知道 宝贝
We know, sweetheart.
我们知道
We know.
特里斯坦 请在休息时间看窗外的风景
Tristan, stare out the window on your own time, please.
抱歉 我曾经梦想有一天能看到亚马逊
Sorry. I used to dream I'd see the Amazon someday.
现在那里除了冰块什么都没有了
Well, there's nothing out there now but frozen lump.
等所有人都走了 我要你像平常的布置一样
As soon as everyone's gone, I want you to set up for the tribunal,
准备一下法庭
as per the usual floor plan.
好的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
菜已经上完了
Service is over.
那是什么
What's that?
这是什么
What's this?
请享用 夜车招待的
Enjoy. Compliments of the Nightcar.
沙玛先生 等一下
Mr. Sharma, wait.
天啊 我...
My God. I...
立刻把梅兰妮找来
Go and get Melanie. Now.
你做出那种事有失身份 奥德丽
That stunt was beneath you, Audrey.
不 并不失身份
No, it really wasn't.
妮基的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about Nikki.
真的
I am.
但一个嫌犯死了
But one suspect is dead,
另一个正以谋杀罪受审 我还漏了什么
and the other is standing trial for murder. What am I missing?
你知道那审判就是个笑话
You know the trial is a joke.
在五英里外的前厢 由一等和二等厢组成的陪审团
It's five miles uptrain, where a jury of First and Second
将审判他们自己人是否杀了我们三个人
get to judge one of their own for killing three of us.
我们
Us?
夜车应该保持中立才对
The Nightcar is supposed to be Switzerland.
你为什么把这事政治化
Why are you politicizing it?
三等厢有权请愿威尔福德
Third has the right to petition Wilford
只要涉及到劳动纠纷和审判规程事宜
in labor disputes and matters of jurisprudence.
我们希望设立新法庭
We want a new tribunal drawn --
每个车厢各派出一名代表
one representative from each class
以及组建一个代表团 旁观审判
and a delegation to observe the trial.
老天 奥德丽
For Christ's sake, Audrey.
听命于威尔福德使你变得冷酷无情
You've grown callous doing Wilford's bidding.
你以前也曾试图改变现状
You used to try to make a difference, too.
我当时就站在这
And I stood right here
听你分享你对夜车的愿景
when you shared your vision of the Nightcar.
威尔福德只看见妓院
Wilford saw a brothel.
而你看见了更高的目标
And you saw a higher purpose.
你说服了他 我是对的
And you persuaded him I was right.
现在我请求你忠于你的愿景
And I am asking you to stay true to your vision.
你给了我们一个熬过悲伤的地方
You give us a place to work through our grief,
列车依靠它
and the train depends on it!
而我们依靠你 靠你向威尔福德发声
And we depend on you, on your voice to Wilford's ear.
向他建议设立新法庭
Recommend a new tribunal.
否则怎么样
Or what?
别逼我威胁你 梅兰妮
Don't make me threaten you, Melanie.
三等厢和列车上所有系统都有联系
Third touches every system on this train.
我们的声音必被听见
We will be heard.
长期假死对妮基造成了什么影响
What has the long-term suspension done to Nikki?
我可以告诉你生理效应
I can tell you the physiological effects --
肾上腺组织坏死 肝功能不全
necrosis of adrenal tissue, hepatic insufficiencies.
她的精神状态呢
But her mental state?
我说不好她本来会不会改善
I can't say whether she would have improved or not.
没足够时间让她完全脱瘾
There wasn't enough time to detox her fully.
我们是否假设他们正有
Are we assuming they're experiencing something
-类似闭锁综合征的体验 -也许吧
- like Locked-in Syndrome? - Maybe.
我们得从减慢唤醒他们的速度开始
We need to start by reviving them much slower.
我们有四百个抽屉
We have 400 drawers.
有一天也许会有四百名沉睡者
Someday we may have 400 Sleepers.
他们不能再出现时精神受创
They can't re-emerge traumatized.
转告威尔福德先生 我在努力了
Tell Mr. Wilford I'm trying.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你还好吧
You okay?
我听说三等厢正请愿在法庭上占有一席之位
I hear Third are petitioning for a spot on the tribunal.
你在考虑这事吗
Are you considering it?
小莱也许能获判应有的罪名
LJ may actually get what she deserves.
你确实在考虑
You are considering it.
让三等厢的人参与审判
A Thirdie on the tribunal?
不 头等厢的人不会满意
No, that's not gonna be popular in First.
头等厢和二等厢要有同样的代表
Equal representation with First and Second.
这就是要求
That's the demand.
你们疯了吗
Are you guys insane?
福爵家族在头等厢势力很大 他们会吓坏的
The Folgers have a lot of power in First. They'll freak out.
你觉得我们现在有阶级分化了吗
You think we have a class divide now?
这可能会毁了一切
This could blow the whole thing up.
能借一步说话吗
Can I borrow you for a second?
行
Yeah.
哈维 你能来掌舵吗
Javi, can you take the helm?
没问题
Sure.
自从蜜蜂死后我们就没干过了
We haven't done that since the bees died.
我似乎发现了一个模式
I'm sensing a bit of a pattern.
天呐 我真希望能开窗
God, I wish I could open a frigging window.
你还记得新鲜空气吗
You remember fresh air?
你记得
You remember...
散步吗
going for walks?
下雨
Rain.
我想念雨声
I miss the sound of rain.
我想念很多事情
I miss so many things.
你要这么做吗
Are you gonna do this?
设立一个新的法庭
Draw a new tribunal?
我只想呼吸
I just want to breathe.
各位乘客请注意
Attention, passengers.
威尔福德先生接受了三等厢的请求
Mr. Wilford has accepted a Third Class petition
为今天的审讯重新设立一个法庭
to redraw the tribunal for today's trial.
将从每个车厢随机抽取一个人的名字
One name has been drawn randomly from each class.
如果你听到了自己的名字 请立即到
If your name is called, please report immediately
乘客服务部代表处报道
to your Hospitality representative.
头等厢 陪审员是伊迪丝·古斯特菲尔德
From First Class, our jurist is Edith Gusterfeld.
二等厢
From Second Class,
小学老师玛丽-伊丽莎白·吉利斯
primary teacher Mary-Elizabeth Gillies.
三等厢的代表是
And representing Third Class --
造纸工人沃特·弗莱明
Papermaker Walter Flemming.
重复一次 伊迪丝·古斯特菲尔德
Again, Edith Gusterfeld,
玛丽-伊丽莎白·吉利斯
Mary-Elizabeth Gillies,
-与沃特·弗莱明 -出发
- and Walter Flemming... - Let's go!
请立即到乘客服务部报道
...please report to Hospitality.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
我们做到了
Oh, we did it.
五分钟后回去清洁
Back on Sanitation in five minutes.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
我也想休息
I want a break, too.
是她
It's her.
谢天谢地 你做到了
Oh, thank God. You made it.
你发现了什么
What did you find out?
没什么可靠的信息 但如果他不在车尾
There's nothing solid, but if he's not in the Tail...
好吧 那她去哪
Okay. So where's she going?
我觉得我找到了一个能帮忙的人
I think I found someone who might help.
-谁 -一个保洁员 叫特伦斯
- Who? - The janitors, a guy named Terence.
给 快 好了 裤子
Here, quick. I got this. Pants.
听着 那个守卫分不出我们的区别
Look. That Jack can't tell us apart.
我会在下次休息前回来 我保证
I'll be back before the next break, I promise.
-对 -好吗
- Yeah. - Okay?
你就保持低调 好吗
You just keep your head down, alright?
-我们会帮你殿后 -好
- We'll watch your back. - Okay.
从这过去 祝你们好运
Okay, go through here. Good luck.
-我要去哪 -市场
- Where am I going? - The Market.
找黄色的蝴蝶 过去就能看到
Look for the yellow butterfly. You'll see it.
好 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
我希望你找到他
I hope you find him.
弗莱明先生
Mr. Flemming.
威尔福德先生感谢您的服务
Mr. Wilford thanks you for your service.
请自便
Please help yourself.
不打声招呼吗
Not saying hello?
我是玛丽 小学老师
I'm Mary, the primary teacher.
我应该感谢您做的手工
I ought to thank you for your craft.
孩子们都很喜欢"新纸日"
The kids love New Paper Day.
伊迪丝·古斯特菲尔德 头等厢的
Edith Gusterfeld, Firstie.
但别因此而反感我
But don't hold that against me.
理解
Understood.
-我喜欢你的耳环 -谢谢 亲爱的
- I like your earrings. - Thank you, dear.
古斯特菲尔德夫人...
Aww! Ms. Gusterfeld...
威尔福德先生难道不知道
Doesn't Mr. Wilford understand
你不能随便更改规则吗
that you can't just change the rules?
我觉得这些规则他有权更改
I guess they're his rules to change.
他遵循人们的意愿
He chose the will of the people.
我们没有意愿
We don't have will.
我们只有秩序
We have order.
我们不是每天都有机会和其他舱位的人交流的
It's not every day we get a chance to mingle with other classes.
三等车厢代表们 如果你们想参加审讯
Third Class delegates, if you want to go to to the trial,
就说出你们的名字和乘客号码
give me your names and passenger numbers.
恭喜
Well, congratulations.
你一定很开心你现在是中产阶级了
You must be happy now that you're bourgeoisie.
不一定 你今天要向瘾君子们进行性敲诈吗
That depends. Are you gonna extort addicts for sex today?
别这样 我的缓刑已经过了
Come on, man. My probation's over.
好吧 我想留下来看珍珠作证
Okay, well, I'd like to stay for Jinju's testimony,
给她一些支持
you know, show her some support.
前车准备好了
They're ready uptrain.
那我们最好出发了 是不是
Well, better get going, then, shouldn't we?
好的 邋遢鬼们
Alright, dirtbags!
我们要出发了 都听好了
We're on the march! Now, listen up!
听着 对
Listen! Right.
你们即将在前列车厢看到
Now, you're gonna see some things uptrain
一些你们不熟悉的东西
that are unfamiliar to you,
比如卫生和自尊
things like hygiene and self-respect.
你们会听到人们说出完整的句子
You will hear people speaking in complete sentences.
不要去打他们 不要去抢他们的随身物品
Now, don't punch them. Don't punch their belongings.
不要乱舔东西
Don't lick things.
我说得够清楚吗
Am I making myself clear?
双手放好 眼睛直视
Now, hands to yourself, eyes forward,
并且记住谁才是指挥者 好吗
and just remember who's carrying the batons, okay?
好的 够了
Alright. That's enough.
好的 大家请排成一队
Okay, everyone, in a line, please!
古斯特菲尔德夫人会跟着头等厢投票
Mrs. Gusterfeld will vote with First.
她会让老师也同意的
She'll get the teacher on board.
别担心
Don't worry.
你没有意识到发生了什么 是吧
You don't see what's happening, do you?
有个想法正在前列车厢中传播 罗伯特
There's an idea traveling uptrain, Robert.
这个想法想要持续存在
It wants to live, this idea.
它想点燃整个列车
It wants to set the train ablaze,
而它只需要一个小火花
and all it needs is a spark.
它只需要用它粗糙的手指
All it needs is to wrap its thick fingers
掐住你女儿的脖子
around your daughter's throat
为了那个工人将她掐死
and choke her out for the working man.
怎么了
What's wrong?
一切都好 亲爱的
Everything's fine, darling.
你看起来好美
You look beautiful.
我们继续来排练你的证词
Let's keep working on your testimony.
其他的就交给我 莱拉
Leave the rest to me, Lilah.
那个变态的杀人团体又带走了一个人
That psycho's Kill Cult took another one.
我们与上帝同行
Juntos, vamos con dios.
坚持住
Hang on.
那个变态的杀人团体又带走了一个人
That psycho's Kill Cult took another one.
-不 我们很饿 -但也不能这样
- No, we are hungry. - Not like this.
我能闻到他们在做吃的
I can smell them cooking.
他们在后面 靠着墙
They're at the back now, against the wall.
该死的食人族
Goddamn cannibals.
来 迈尔斯 上去吧
Come on, Miles. Up you go.
-我们会没事的 -我们需要你帮忙
- We'll be alright. - We need your help.
快去阻止他们
Put a stop to them now.
给
Here you are.
欢迎来到三等厢
Welcome to Third.
她浑身散发着清洁小队的臭气
She reeks of Sanitation.
原来你是这么出来的啊
So that's how you got out.
阿斯特丽德不肯说
Astrid wouldn't say.
很好
Good.
我们如此铤而走险就是为了找到莱顿
We risked this for one reason -- to find Layton.
他没回车尾吗
He's not back in the Tail?
说是回了 但其实没有
They're saying he is, but, no, he isn't.
我们觉得他进了抽屉
We think he's in a drawer.
所以说...
So, um...
这个男人站了出来
the man comes forward,
破解了列车史上最大的案子
solves the biggest crime in train history.
为什么还要把他关进抽屉呢
Why would they put him in a drawer?
也许是他发现了不可告人的秘密
Maybe he turned over the wrong rock.
也许他已经死了
Or maybe he's dead.
也许是他惹恼了威尔福德
Maybe he pissed off Wilford
害自己被处死
and, uh, got his head stuck out a port, huh?
他是打不死的 你见过他
He's not the dying type. You met him.
有意思
Funny.
我们刚刚正好聊到了抽屉的事
We were just talking about The Drawers.
我们能进去吗
Can we get in?
今天时机不错
Might not be a bad day for it.
因为审判的事 安保很薄弱
Security's lean 'cause of the trial.
那...
Yeah, well...
管他的
What the hell?
我们就去抽屉吧
Let's hit The Drawers.
我们与三等厢的好人没有过节
We have no issue with the good people of Third,
但如果他们只想制造骚乱
but if all they have to do is make a bit of noise
而我们突然打算改写列车神圣的规矩
and suddenly we're rewriting the enshrined rules of the train,
那我们就都有麻烦了
then we all have a problem.
恕我直言 福爵先生 你这么说
All due respect, Mr. Folger, are you speaking
是出自一位担忧的公民 还是一位害怕的父亲
as a concerned citizen or a scared daddy?
-都有 -我们都支持福爵一家
- Both. - We all stand with the Folgers.
如果三等厢针对我们的小孩 他们也会如此
As they'd stand with us if Third came for our children.
我的职责是维持规矩 不是制定规矩
My job is to uphold the rules, not to make them.
威尔福德先生把自己封闭在了前车
Mr. Wilford locked himself away uptrain.
他与现实脱节了
The man is out of touch.
他有让我们所有人活下去的能力
He's got the skills to keep us all alive.
你们有什么
What have you got?
我有作为早期投资者身份的四亿美元
I got $400 million in early investor status
以及如果事关我的生死 我能制造很多麻烦
and a whole world of pain when it comes to my survival.
请不要误会我们
Please don't misunderstand us.
愿威尔福德的永动机永不停息
May Wilford run his engine for as long as the track holds.
但日常运行 正义 资源 车尾
But day-to-day operations, justice, resources, the Tail...
或许这些问题在这里解决更好
maybe these matters would be better handled here,
因为这里会受到影响
where their effects are felt.
那梅兰妮·卡维尔怎么办
And what about Melanie Cavill?
她会是第一个下台的人
She'd be the first to go.
他们是在谈论煽动叛乱的事
So they're talking about sedition.
指挥官是怎么回应的
How did the commander respond?
他持中立态度
Uh, well, he didn't agree or -- or disagree.
他主要是冷眼看着我们
He mostly just, uh, stared at us coldly,
不过我得说 很有效果
which, I won't lie, is very effective.
你不用去参加庭审吗
Don't you need to get to the trial?
我要去的
I do.
我们会加快为你翻修
We'll speed up those renovations for you,
威尔福德先生感谢你的服务
and Mr. Wilford thanks you for your service.
亲爱的 该走了
Honey. It's time to go.
记得要进行眼神交流
Make eye contact.
我知道
I know.
-真诚点 -我知道
- Be sincere. - I know!
-老套的眼泪攻势就行 -不要眼泪攻势
- Trite tears are okay. - Not trite tears.
-眼泪攻势 -我会哭出眼泪 不会说出眼泪
- Contrite tears. - Well, I'll be crying them, not saying them,
这样你可以结束后再来批评我
so you can just criticize me after.
过来 我的两个莱拉
Come here, my Liliahs.
全体起立
All rise.
肃静
Please settle.
大家都知道
As we are all aware,
当永动机的秩序遭到犯罪 阴谋和渎职威胁时
tribunals are convened when the Order of our Eternal Engine
我们会就召开审判
is threatened by crime, conspiracy, or negligence.
小莱拉·福爵
Lilah Folger Junior,
你被控犯下两起谋杀案
you stand accused of two counts of murder.
请坐
Please be seated.
审判开始
This tribunal is now in session.
被告被捕后
Once the accused was apprehended,
司闸员就彻底搜查了
the Brakemen conducted a full and thorough search
福爵的住处
of the Folgers' quarters.
我们找到了本案中最关键的证据
There we found the most striking evidence in the case.
小莱拉的首饰盒里
Hidden in Lilah Junior's jewelry box
藏着保存完好的
were the particularly preserved
两名死者切割下来的生殖器
severed penises of two male victims.
肖恩·怀斯被一根细带捆绑
Sean Wise was bound and choked multiple times
并掐至窒息多次
with a thin ligature.
他的生殖器被切下时...
He was very much alive when his genitals were...
他还活着
chopped off.
那场景真是惨绝人寰
It was nothing you ever want to see.
他冰冷的尸身就这么盯着我
He was staring back at me through the cold,
没有四肢
limbless and...
没有下体
...and dickless.
埃里克一直关注的都是小莱拉
The whole time, Erik's focus was Lilah Junior.
我虽然是他的人质 但也几乎是她的人质
I was as much her hostage as I was his.
这就是埃里克和小莱一直以来想要的
That was what they wanted, Erik and LJ,
让我们死于虚妄的愤怒中
to kill us all in a nihilistic rage.
但是永动机还在
But the Eternal Engine is still here.
接下来 请夜车的奥德丽小姐
We will now hear from Miss Audrey of the Nightcar,
代表一位被害人发言
speaking on behalf of one of the victims.
我将知无不言
I will tell the whole truth.
她的名字不叫"被害人"
Her name was not "Victim."
她叫妮克莱特·吉奈特 妮基
Her name was Nicolette Genêt -- Nikki.
她唱歌跑调 还很善良
She sang off-key, and she was kind as a rule,
但是你们几乎都不在乎她
but few of you care up here.
对你们来说 她只是后车厢的一个死去的女孩
To you, she's just some dead girl from downtrain.
你们需要关注三等厢的人
Well, you need to care about the lives of Third,
因为我们每周七天 每天三班倒
because seven days a week, three shifts a day,
保持轴承润滑 防止严寒霜冻
we keep the bearings greased and the cold at bay.
我们生孩子需要抽签
We draw straws to have children,
我们会死于可预防的意外
and we die from preventible accidents
你们能轻松治好的病 却能要我们的命
and diseases you get treatment for.
我来这里费了不少周折
I haven't come to this place easily.
我们离开芝加哥时
When we left Chicago,
需要威尔福德先生的铁律才能活下来
we needed Mr. Wilford's iron order to survive,
但在绕了近19圈后
but almost 19 revolutions later...
七年了 我了解你们所有人
seven years, I know all of you,
我知道 我们需要拯救我们的灵魂
and I know we need to save our souls.
找回你们的同情心
Find your compassion.
向列车上所有人发出一条信息
Send a message to this entire train
正义不只属于富人
that justice is not reserved for the rich.
人人都能得到正义 妮基也能
There can be justice for all, for Nikki.
她的名字是妮基
Her name was Nikki.
肃静
Order!
肃静 拜托
Order! Please!
我们稍作休息
We will take a brief recess,
回来后 我们将有请被告发言
and when we return, we will hear from the accused.
大夫 我能帮囚犯擦地板吗
Oh, Doctor, can I swab the floor for the prisoners?
不用了 我想回到庭审上去
No, it's okay. I want to get back to the trial.
嗯 可怜的姑娘
Oh, yeah. Poor girl.
你刚有去听吗 抱歉
Were you listening? Sorry.
真令人心碎
It's heartbreaking.
谢谢 确实是
Thank you. Yes, it really is.
用点力
Come on. Come on.
来
Come on.
你们好 可怜虫们
Hello, you poor buggers.
他在哪个抽屉里
Which one's he in?
自己找
Figure it out.
该死
Shit.
肯定有名单吧
There's -- There's got to be a list here somewhere.
快来
Come on. Quick.
那是什么 你们去哪
What's that? Where are you going?
抱歉 车尾人
Sorry, Tailie.
你们趁火打劫
You're robbing the place.
你能帮我找到他吗 拜托了
Can you help me find him, please?
我们不是针对你
Don't take this personally, huh?
别被抓了
And don't get caught.
不 等下
No, wait, wait.
得走了
Got to go.
靠
Shit!
莱拉
Lilah.
不管你在暗地里做什么 都别做了
Whatever you're doing behind closed doors, don't.
我给你讲个福爵家的故事
Let me tell you a Folger family story.
小莱7岁的时候 她取出了罗伯特的眼睛
When LJ was 7, she put out Robert's eye.
用叉子在他脸上乱戳
Lashed out with a fork and punctured it all over his face.
即使胶状物从他脸上流下
And even as the jelly was running down his cheek,
他在她发脾气的时候全程抱着她 保护她
he held her through the tantrum, protecting her.
所以你继续进行你乘客服务部的走过场审判
So you go ahead with your Hospitality show trial
到时后果自负
and prepare to suffer the consequences.
因为你惹的是我的血脉
Because you're messing with my bloodline.
借过
Excuse me.
你在哪 莱顿
Where are you, Layton?
你在哪
Where are you?
我发誓会说实话
I swear to tell the truth.
我爱埃里克·索托
I-I loved Erik Sotto.
或者说至少我认为是这样
Or at least I think I did.
我内心的困惑 疼痛和恐惧
The -- The confusion, the ache in my guts, the fear,
那就是爱 不是吗
that is love, isn't it?
埃里克跟我说是的
Erik told me it was.
埃里克控制着我 而我...
Erik had a power over me, and I --
他让我看着他做可怕的事情
He made me watch him do terrible things.
我仍能听到那些男人求他住手
And I-I can still hear those men begging for it to end.
但埃里克说恐惧让人诚实
Uh, but Erik said fear makes people honest.
我想那是真的
I think that's true.
肖恩·怀斯 在他死前 他说他是一个线人
Sean Wise, just before he died, said that he was an informant...
他是威尔福德先生的间谍
...A spy for Mr. Wilford.
见鬼
Shit.
老天啊
Dios mío.
肖恩说阴影和谎言
Sean said that shadows and lies
占据了我们美丽的列车 从头至尾
were taking over our beautiful train from tip to Tail,
从农业区到抽屉间
from Ag-Sec to The Drawers.
他说"400个能震惊我们所有人的秘密"
"400 secrets that rock us to the rails," He said,
但他绝不会说出来
but he would never spill them.
米娅
Mia?
米娅 我的天
Mia. Oh, my God.
这段话我能说给威尔福德先生吗
Can I say this part to Mr. Wilford?
可以 他有在听
Yes, he's following along.
我很抱歉我有参与此次悲剧
I am so sorry for the part that I played in this tragedy.
我在本该发声的时候选择了沉默
I was silent when I should have spoken,
但肖恩·怀斯为了拯救黑暗中的人类
but Sean Wise gave his life to save humanity
而牺牲了自己 那黑暗差点将我吞噬
from the darkness that almost swallowed me whole.
不 不 不
Oh, no. No, no, no.
如果列车能宽恕我
If the train shows me mercy...
我保证我也会为它做出贡献
...I promise to do my part for her, too.
我只能说这么多
That's all I can say.
全体起立
All rise.
审判员现在将去进行商讨
The tribunal will now break to deliberate.
莱顿
Layton.
刚才怎么回事
What the hell was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是说
I mean...
也许肖恩发现抽屉是在做实验
Maybe Sean found out that The Drawers are experimental.
也许他跟她说了名单
Maybe he told her about the list.
这就改变了一切 对吗
Well, that changes the calculus, doesn't it?
这都怪她
This is all her fault.
从一开始 我就不该来这儿
From the beginning, I shouldn't even be here.
闭嘴 哈维尔
Shut up, Javier.
你有其他选择吗
Do you have another option?
没有
No.
不 我没有
No, I don't.
我又没和她睡 对吗
I'm not sleeping with her, am I?
莱顿
Layton?
莱顿 我来了 莱顿
Layton, I'm here. Layton.
莱顿 莱顿 莱顿
Layton, Layton, Layton.
莱顿 我来了
Layton, I'm here.
二等厢走廊真香啊
Oh, the sweet smell of Second Class corridors.
你的结婚新家
Your new bridal home, eh?
来吃晚餐吧
Come for dinner.
二等厢每晚都能有甜点
Second Class rations get dessert every night.
怎么了
What?
奥斯维勒
Osweiller.
-莱顿 -是车尾人
- Layton. - It's a Tailie!
小奥 小奥 放开她
Oz! Oz, get off her!
你是提尔 对吗 莱顿
You're Till, right? Layton.
-他怎么在这儿 -他几乎没有心跳
- Why is he in here? - His heartbeat's barely there.
他应该在车尾的
He's supposed to be in the Tail!
莱顿 莱顿
Layton. Layton.
莱顿 你能听到我吗
Layton, can you hear me?
莱顿 莱顿 是我 莱顿
Layton. Layton. It's me. Layton.
莱顿 莱顿
Layton, Layton.
莱顿
Layton.
我们得赶紧离开
We got to get out of here now.
肃静
Order!
请安静
Quiet, please.
小莱拉·福爵
Lilah Folger Junior,
法庭现在将宣布裁决结果
the tribunal will now announce your verdict.
陪审团一致决定
By unanimous decision,
我们认为小莱拉·福爵
we find Lilah Folger Junior...
所有罪名都成立
guilty on all counts.
别无他法
There's no choice.
这是她在最坏情况下的要求
It's what she asked for in the worst case.
她就不该管的
She should've left it.
She should've just left it alone.
肃静 肃静
Order! Order!
大家肃静
Order, everyone!
我们收到了一条威尔福德先生的信息
We have a message from Mr. Wilford.
考虑到被告还很年轻
In light of the young age of the accused...
威尔福德先生选择减免小莱拉·福爵的判决
...Mr. Wilford commutes the sentence of Lilah Folger Junior
将她送还给她的父母
and remands her to the custody of her parents.
谢天谢地 你安全了
Thank God. You're safe.
请冷静
Please calm down!
肃静 肃静
Order! Order! Please!
大家保持冷静
Everyone remain calm!
请保持冷静 庭审结束
Please remain calm! This trial is over.
请保持冷静
Please remain calm.
好了 我只能到这儿了
Alright. As far as I go.
-什么 -我得走了
- What? - No, I got to go.
-你去哪 -我就是得走了
- Where are you going? - Just -- I got to go.
-在哪 -继续走
- Where is it? - Keep going.
她就在前面
She's down there.
来 莱顿
Come on, Layton.
我扶着你 我扶着你
I've got you. I've got you.
乔茜
Josie.
你得把他藏起来
You need to hide him.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
他们把他关进了抽屉
They drawered him.
不准抛下我 好吗
Don't you give up on me now, okay?
我会回来的
I'll be back. I'll be back.
I'll be back.
你怎么从车尾出来的
How'd you get out of the Tail?
车尾需要信任你 扎拉
The Tail needs to trust you, Zarah.
我会照顾他的
I'll look after him.
我得送你到楼上去
Got to get you upstairs.
在我放你回到你父母身边之前
Before I release you to your parents...
威尔福德先生要我
Mr. Wilford has asked me
强调守口如瓶的重要性
to stress the importance of discretion.
别把他的抽屉秘密说出去
Oh, so don't spill all of his Drawer secrets?
肖恩·怀斯具体跟你说了什么
What did Sean Wise tell you exactly?
那是我和威尔福德先生之间的事 不是吗
That's between me and Mr. Wilford, isn't it?
他为了帮你冒了很大的风险
He's taking an extraordinary risk in helping you.
三等厢
Third Class?
他们会翻篇的
I think they'll get over it.
我是说你 小莱
I mean you, LJ.
我指的是放你走
I mean letting you walk free.
威尔福德关照我
Wilford looked out for me, so...
我也会关照他
I'll look out for him.
我能走了吗
Can I go now?
-爸爸 -莱拉
- Daddy! - Lilah.
结束了
It's over.
-你安全了 -都结束了
- You're safe. - It's all over.
-真是场噩梦 -你安全了
- What a nightmare. - You're safe.
我爱你
I love you.
奥斯维勒
Osweiller?
该死
Shit.
下不为例
Never again.
-下不为例 -下不为例
- Never again. - Never again.